# **Patryk Ernest Nowak**

# Frontend Developer

© +48 791-586-632

patryk.ernest.nowak@gmail.com

② Lublin/Warszawa/remote



## **ABOUT ME**

I am a self-taught programmer who has been interested in technology and computers from a young age. I have been programming and creating websites for two years. Independence, persistence and patience are the features of my personality. My goal is to achieve an expert level by continuously improving my skills and keeping up with industry best practices.

## SKILLS

HTML/CSS · JavaScript (ES6) · TypeScript

React (React Router • Axios • Context API • Redux Toolkit)

SASS/SCSS (with BEM) · TailwindCSS · CSS Modules · Styled Components

AI/LLM/LangChain.js • SQL • Vite.js • Gulp.js • Parcel.js • GIT/GITHUB • Postman • Docker Mobile First • RWD • AllY • 3RD PARTY LIBRARIES (Swiper, AOS, Moment etc.)

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Freelance 02/2023 - Present

# Frontend Developer

- Create visually appealing and responsive user interfaces.
- Implement best practices for efficient rendering and resource utilization.
- Implement interactive features and dynamic behavior using JavaScript.
- · Test and ensure that web applications work seamlessly across various browsers and platforms.
- Use version control systems like Git to manage and track changes in codebase.

**Projects** See more projects on <a href="https://www.pendev.me/#myworks">www.pendev.me/#myworks</a>

## Frontend Mentor Challenges CHECK LIVE SITE

HTML/CSS/JS TypeScript React SCSS TailwindCSS CSS Modules Vite.js API

Here you can find a showcase of my front-end skills, where I try to practice the technical skills.

I have gathered. This collection features my solutions to various Frontend Mentor challenges.

Here you can find a showcase of my front-end skills, where I try to practice the technical skills I have gathered. This collection features my solutions to various Frontend Mentor challenges, each providing a real-life workflow experience. From designs, assets, and style requirements. All solutions are created by me based on my knowledge.

M-Data www.m-data.me

HTML/CSS/JS TypeScript SCSS BEM Parcel.js Swiper.js A11Y OOP MVC

Individual project - **SPA** Portfolio dedicated to Data Analyst. The main objective was to present the analyst's biography, skills and Power BI reports. My wholly designed and developed site was implemented with **Object-Oriented Programming** approach and **Model-View-Controller Pattern**. To build it, I used **Parcel.js**.

# Ten Vape www.tenvape.pl

HTML/CSS/JS SCSS BEM Gulp Swiper.js A11Y MOBILE FIRST

Business website for a local e-cigarette store. My first commercial project entirely designed and implemented by myself with full **hosting configuration**.

In implementation, I focused on improving accessibility and performance.

I used external libraries such as **Swiper.js** and build it with **Gulp.js**.

DB Schenker/central team 05/2021 - 09/2023

# **Logistics specialist**

- Support, coordination and control of the work of branches in Poland on the implementation of business processes and preparation.
- Analysis of statements, procedures and reports.
- Collaborating with the wider analyst team to deliver optimized business solutions.
- Participating in international business project to align of the implemented software with current business standards.
- · Testing mobile, web and desktop applications.

# **EDUCATION**

UMCS in Lublin



2016-2021

Dietetics

2013-2016

> UMCS in Lublin

**Computer Science** 

2011-2012

## LANGUAGES

Polish Native English B2

# STRENGTHS

### Eager to learn new skills

As a person who is starting out, I am constantly seeking for new ways to grow and expand my skill set.

#### Not afraid of failure

Strong believer in the mantra that we learn from our mistakes.

# Time management

I always set aside time to plan my week and distribute the workload by days so that I can simultaneously meet deadliness and maintain my well-being.

#### **Problem Solving**

Applied strong problem-solving skills in designing usable, aesthetically pleasing interfaces, leading to increased user engagement.

# HOBBIES

FI motor sports snowboarding & skiing board games technology trends